小聲點 你會吵到莉莉
Shh! You'll wake Lily.
你是有多醉啊
How drunk are you?
我跟你說三次她出去校外旅行了
I told you three times she's on that school trip.
你要是不這么小聲說
I'd feel more confident
-你的話會更有說服力一點 -你說得合理
- if you weren't also whispering. - Fair point.
你... 你擦了口紅嗎
Are -- Are you wearing lipstick?
我是擦了指甲油嗎
Am I wearing nail polish?
我們算是出去瘋了一晚
So, we kind of had a crazy night out.
本來一開始只是
It started off at this little
去一家我聽人說的隱秘地下酒吧
under-the-radar speakeasy I heard about.
他網上搜了"我家附近的酷酒吧"
Uh, he Googled "Cool bars near me."
反正呢 我們遇到了一幫20歲小年輕
Anyway, we met a group of 20-somethings
大家相談甚歡
that took a shine to us.
他們帶我們進入了地下派對
They introduced us to the world of underground parties
與一杯雞尾酒要18塊的世界
and $18 cocktails.
-真的是太燒了 -是燃
- It was so burnt. - Lit.
-太燃 -燃
- Lit. - Lit.
我們去的這些酒吧 有半數我都記不得了
I don't even remember half these bars.
我們昨晚還去了醫院嗎
Did we go to a hospital last night?
塔克奶奶的招牌解宿醉秘方
Okay, Grandma Tucker's hangover remedy --
在你的舌下放小塊黃油 把脖子往后仰
put a pat of butter underneath your tongue, tip your head back,
我把辣醬往你鼻子灌
and I'll pour the hot sauce up your nose.
等等等等
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
-是賓克發來的群短信 -什么
- That's a group text from Binker. - What?
-是的 -天啊
- Mm-hmm. - Oh, my gosh.
大伙們今晚還想再一起去派對呢
The gang wants to get back together and party tonight.
你還說他們看到我們
And you said we'd never hear from them
在丹尼酒吧燈光下的丑樣后 就會斷絕聯系
after they saw us in that horrible Denny's lighting.
我們的回應得百分百恰到好處
Okay, we have to play this exactly right --
不能顯得自己死命想巴著人家
We don't want to come off too eager,
但又得讓他們知道我們愿意一起嗨
but we also want to let 'em know we're down to mob.
-要親命了 -小卡 你知道我們的規矩
- Oh, my God. - Cam, you know our rule,
絕對不連續兩晚出去野
we never go out two nights in a row.
-我知道 但這是... -我們今晚還要去
- Yeah, I know, but this is... - We're already pushing it
聽系列講座呢 這已經算很勉強了
by going to that lecture series tonight.
什么系列講座
What lecture series?
美儲聯主席首席助手的講座
Alan Greenspan's top aide.
我們買了季票 因為我們想要最好的座位
We bought the season pass so we'd get premium seating
去聽"幽默作家弗蘭·拉伯維治的諷刺之夜"
to "A Night of Sarcasm with Fran Lebowitz."
大家都要去呢
Oh, everyone's in.
還用了不同膚色豎拇指 年輕人就是反歧視
Look at all those thumbs of colors. They're so woke.
"我們不去 下次見"
"We're out. Catch you next time"?
米奇爾
Mitchell.
你怎么可以這樣
How could you?
小聲點暴走 別吵醒莉莉了
Storm out softly. You'll wake Lily.
早啊 老婆 別在意我這一身加州理工裝備
Morning, honey. Don't mind all the Caltech gear.
我只是想給艾麗克斯驚喜 帶她去吃午飯
I figured I'd surprise Alex at school and take her to lunch.
學期末這時候你要去給她驚喜嗎
Surprise her? At the end of the semester?
親愛的 她應該在忙于各種期末考之中吧
Honey, she's probably in the middle of exams.
她絕對會...
She's gonna be...
欣喜若狂
thrilled.
你有看過自己的錄像 是你在觀看時
Have you ever seen a video of yourself
才發現自己當時沒意識到穿著有多難看嗎
wearing something you didn't realize was unflattering?
我最近有了這樣的經驗
Well, that happened to me recently, and...
而難看的是我的性格
it was my personality.
千百年來 人類一直渴望能像
For centuries, man has longed to rule the air
偉大的飛鼠般掌握騰空的能力
like the majestic squirrel.
一切將在今日終止
The wait ends today.
不行
Nope.
那如果我們...
Uh, but what if we --
-一樣沒卵用 -媽
- Doesn't matter. - Hey, Mom.
我戴這個是好看的對吧
I can pull this off, right?
讓我來幫你調整
Let me. Oh.
我們不在家
Ah, we're not home.
我決定要不那么負面
I made a decision to be less negative.
這是嶄新的我 對一切都說"好"的女人
It's the new me, the girl who says "Yes."
朋友周末去墨西哥玩 在幫忙看
Friend went to Mexico for the weekend.
我還在拿捏那個平衡點
I'm finding the level.
好帥啊 像《邁阿密風云》里似的
Crockett and Tubbs, you look snazzy.
謝謝... 你的話是稱贊吧
Thanks... I think.
我在試著打扮自己
I'm trying to step up my game.
我最近開始跟工作認識的一個人交往
I started seeing someone from work.
親愛的 我覺得呢
Oh, honey. I don't know
跟工作認識的人交往感覺不太...
if I think that's such a good idea that --
沒事沒事 我贊成
Never mind. I approve.
如果我媽知道事情的全部 我不信她會同意
I doubt my mom would approve if she knew the whole story.
泳池工
Pool boy.
我這里需要新毛巾
I need more towels.
女士 馬上來
Right away, ma'am.
搞定 我剛同意了另一個設計
Done. I just approved another design.
世界上最豪華的狗窩
The most luxurious dog bed yet.
我稱它為...
I call it...
狗窩之巔
The Top of the Bark.
真好啊 你現在可以在家營運新公司
Ah, that's nice that you can run your new company at home
就能穿著只能在家穿的衣服了
in clothes that you can only wear at home.
當男人到了某個年齡后
When men get to a certain age,
他們就不再在乎外表
they stop trying.
我看過這情況了
I've seen it before.
先從服裝開始
First, it starts with the clothes,
然后是身材 最后是腦子
then the body, then the brain.
但我不能跟杰提任何一點意見
But I can't say anything to Jay,
因為每當提到他的外表問題
because when it comes to his appearance,
他總是格外敏感
he's very sensitive.
親愛的 我回來啦
Mi amor, I'm back.
歡迎回來
Welcome home.
你不喜歡 對吧
You hate it, right?
我去剃了 就是個笑話
I'll shave it. It's a joke.
我個傻逼
Stupid!
日安 各位
Good dawning, all.
我眼前的這是什么
What am I looking at?
獸醫擔心你會咬自己嗎
Is the vet worried you're gonna bite yourself?
這是傳統的都鐸式領子
It's a traditional Tudor collar.
我請求加入學校的伊麗莎白時代社團
I'm pledging my school's Elizabethan Society,
這是他們要求的入團羞辱儀式
and I have to wear this as a hazing ritual.
我覺得還行啊
I don't hate it.
我覺得這讓你的腦袋看起來
I think it makes your head
像是那種高檔餅干之類的
look like one of those fancy cookies.
我還得背誦幾段莎士比亞的獨白
I also have to recite several Shakespearean monologues
然后給學校食堂加一點下流裝飾
and festoon our dining hall with some bawdy bunting.
這年代的羞辱儀式是怎么回事
What happened to hazing?
以前都是很爺們的玩法 你懂的
It used to be macho stuff, you know,
比如讓人從你的肚臍眼喝烈酒
like making a guy drink a shot out of your belly button
或者是大家屁股夾著橘子傳來傳去
or passing an orange around only using your butt cheeks.
這可是學校里最難進的社團之一
Look. It's one of the most selective groups on campus.
我不想話說太早觸自己霉頭
I don't want to jinx it,
但一周之后 我很有可能就在學習
but a week from now, I could be learning
秘密小步舞曲的舞步了呢
the steps of the secret minuet.
這就是學校消滅校園霸凌的后果
This is what happens when you eliminate campus bullying.
杰 你覺得如何
Jay, what do you think?
我們去好餐廳吃頓午飯
We'll go out for a nice lunch,
稍微打扮一下
dress up a little bit.
這感覺是在攻擊我啊
This feels like an attack.
我最多也只能婉轉到這個地步了
All right, that's as gentle as I can go,
我是哥倫比亞人 不是加拿大人
I am Colombian, not Canadian.
我剛收到俱樂部寄來的電郵
I got an e-mail from the club.
一些老人要在周間早晨占用我們的高球練習場
The older players have taken over the driving range
來練習室外地滾球
for bocce weekday mornings.
那又怎么樣啦 你們可以晚點再打高爾夫啊
So what? You can play golf later.
不行 我們有一個群組
No, we got a whole group --
叫日出揮桿手
the Sunrise Swingers.
我們每天6點見面 打一桶球
We meet there at 6:00, hit a bucket.
群組里的一個女成員還要做背心制服呢
One of the gals is making up tank tops.
太好了 更多休閑服
Oh, yay. More casual clothes.
這樣不行 我要去俱樂部
No, I'm going down there,
尋求其他高球手的支持
get the support of some of the other golfers.
-或許我們還能搶回時間段 -好主意啊
- Maybe I can fight this thing. - Okay, good idea,
但別忘了俱樂部有著裝要求啊
but don't forget that there is a dress code at the club.
他們很可能已經撤銷這規定了
They probably already overturned it.
自從他們不再往小便斗里放冰塊
Ah, the whole place went to hell
那地方就一落千丈了
when they stopped putting ice in the urinals.
在尿尿時摧毀某樣東西
There's just something about destroying a thing
讓人有種成就感
while you're taking a pee
那令男人覺得自己雄風不減
that makes a man feel like a man.
你好啊
Oh, well, hello there.
-爸爸 你怎么來啦 -你好
- Uh, Dad. What are you doing here? - Hi.
我想帶你去吃午飯
I thought I'd take you to lunch.
我不只是為了吃午飯
It wasn't just about lunch.
在三個孩子中 我一直覺得跟艾麗克斯最不親近
Of my three kids, I've always felt least connected with Alex.
我擔心我倆之間的距離
And I'm afraid that the distance between us
在她畢業后會越拉越遠
might grow after she graduates.
天啊 她快畢業了
Wow. Graduates?
不過短短十年前
It was just, like, 10 years ago
她才第一次上大學課程
when she took her first college course.
你應該先打電話說一聲的
I really wish you would've called.
我今天去不了吃午飯 我快遲到了
I can't go to lunch today. I'm late for...
-要參加個活動 -所以你打扮得這么漂亮嗎
- an event. - Is that why you're all dressed up?
對 不過沒什么大不了的
Yeah. But it's no big deal.
對了 你看你們校報了嗎
B-T-dubs, have you seen your school paper?
你們畢業致辭的學生代表居然是只黑猩猩
Apparently, your valedictorian is a chimp.
這種大新聞怎么沒上頭條
How is that not bigger news?
這是假報紙 爸爸
It's a fake paper, Dad.
這周是畢業生惡作劇周
It's senior prank week.
真希望我早點知道
Oh. I wish I'd known that
但我已經給你媽發了這條短信
before I sent your mom this text.
"猩猩開始進化了 快把香蕉藏好"
"It's starting. Hide the bananas."
-鬧哪樣 -開普勒獎
- Seriously?! - The Kepler Award?
你就是要去參加這個嗎
Is this where you're going,
看起來是很重要的獎項啊
'cause it looks like it's a big deal?
只是給決賽選手辦的無聊歡迎會
It's just a boring reception for finalists.
我就喜歡歡迎會
Well, I love a good reception.
幾點開始
What time are we expected?
我應該不能帶嘉賓入場
Oh, I don't think I'm allowed to bring guests.
這里寫著"歡迎學生家屬出席"
Says here, "Families welcome."
但我當時沒回復要帶
But I didn't RSVP.
這里寫著"不必預約"
Says here, "Walk-ins encouraged."
這傳單的信息量真足
What an informative flyer.
太棒了 我們去吧
Awesome. Let's do this.
瑜伽這玩意啊
Yoga, right?
沒有贏家 也沒有輸家
No winners, no losers,
沒有"誰最優秀"
no "Who's best?"
你想要我告訴你 你是唯一一個
You want me to tell you that you are the only one
不需要老師幫助的人嗎
that didn't need help from the teacher?
真的嗎
Was I?
-詹妮絲 你好 -你好啊
- Janice. Hi. - Hi.
這位是克萊爾 我先生的女兒
This is Claire, my husband's daughter.
-你好 -你好
- Hi. - Hi.
那歌洛莉亞應該算是你的繼母 對吧
So, that makes Gloria kind of like your stepmother.
對 但我們不搞這一套
Yeah, we don't do that.
話說
Um, anyways,
你的新男友怎么樣
how is your new boyfriend?
很好
Pretty great.
不過我對于我倆的年齡差
I do feel a little awkward
是感到有些尷尬啦
about the age difference, though.
怎么個尷尬法
Ooh, which way are we talking?
他...才20歲出頭
He's, uh, in his early 20s.
爽爆了
Noice!
差那么多不會尷尬嗎
Isn't that embarrassing?
才不會 勇敢去愛
No. I say go for it.
我喜歡這個新克萊爾
Ooh, I like this new Claire
她不會對每件事都持反對意見
that says "Yes" to things.
換做以前 你會...
Before, you would be like, uh...
形容令人不爽怎么說來著
what is the word for grouchy?
現在這已經不重要了
I don't think it matters now.
20歲出頭小鮮肉啊
Early 20s, huh.
在那年紀 還沒被地心引力打敗
Well, you're still beating gravity at that point.
所有部位一定都在該在的地方 沒變形
I bet everything is right where it should be.
-沒錯 -是的
- Oh, yes. - Yeah.
看看他給我發的腹肌自拍
Check out this selfie he sent of his abs.
靠
Damn!
跟注重自己外表的人在一起真好
It's so nice to be with someone who takes care of himself,
不像我這年紀的男人 不修邊幅
not like the guys my age.
可不是嘛
Tell me about it.
杰開始有點不在意了
Jay's starting to give up a little bit.
從他穿的衣服就能看出來
You know, in the way that he's dressing.
不如你把男友帶來我家 提醒一下杰
Why don't you bring your guy by the house to remind Jay
女人喜歡努力維持外表的男人
that women like a man that make a little effort.
-我們今天有空 方便嗎 -太棒了
- Um, well, we're free later today, if that works. - Perfect.
克萊爾 你也來 你就能幫我
And, Claire, you come, too, so that you help me
把杰推往正確的方向
nudge Jay in the right direction.
我可不希望我的第一次"拒絕"
Well, I wouldn't want my first "No"
-是對我繼母說的 -不是說了不搞這一套嗎
- to be to my stepmother. - I said we're not doing that.
小卡 快點
Cam, hurry!
我們到得夠早的話
If we get there early enough,
就能提交一個關于美儲聯主席的問題
we get to submit a question about Greenspan.
我有個關于滯脹的好問題
I got a doozy about stag-flation.
-聽我說完 -你
- Just hear me out. - You...
-我們決定好了的 -不 是你決定好了
- We decided... - No, you decided.
而且米奇爾 我們昨晚玩得那么開心
And, Mitchell, we had so much fun last night.
莉莉還有一晚才回來
Lily's gone for one more night.
咱們出去吧 走啦 找點樂子嘛
Let's go out! Come on. Have some fun.
打破我們的"連續兩晚"約定嗎
And break our two-night-in-a-row rule?
才不 絕不 我不要
No, no. I don't think so.
得了 你昨晚才睡了兩個小時
Okay, you slept two hours last night.
你知道當你太累時會撞墻上吧
You know you hit a wall when you get overtired.
-可不是鬧著玩的 -你知道我怎么想嗎
- It's very intense. - You know what I think this is?
我覺得你在擔心自己跟不上
I think you're worried that you can't keep up
我和我的青春活力
with me and my youthful spirit.
那天你還管冰箱叫冰盒子來著
The other day, you called a refrigerator an icebox.
那才不老 那叫鄉村風情
That's not old, that's country cute.
-行吧 -面對現實吧 你生來老成
- Okay. - Let's face it. You were born 50,
而我卻在內心永葆青春
and I've always been young at heart.
你知道嗎 也許這就是我們初次見面時
And you know what? Maybe that's what attracted you
我吸引你的原因... 我的少年魅力
to me in the first place... my boyish charm.
而你則是個成熟滄桑的男人 來到我身邊...
And you were an older, seasoned man who came and...
引誘我 羅賓遜先生
seduced me, Mr. Robinson.
好 行 這真是個"新潮"的比喻
Okay, yeah, that's a youthful reference.
你該和你的新朋友炫耀一下
You should trot that out with your new friends.
小卡 你每次都是這樣
Cam, this is so you, okay?
你把自己累垮了
You're running yourself ragged
就為了證明自己還年輕
trying to remain young.
我是說 接受自己變老了一點點這個事實
I mean, there's nothing wrong with accepting the fact
沒什么不好的
that you're getting a little older.
除非你承認得太早
Unless you're admitting it too soon.
你不會想某天一拍腦袋想
You don't want to look up one day and think,
"我是不是忘了什么事"
"Oh, what did I forget to do?
"沒錯 享受生活"
"Oh, yeah. Live."
行了 如果你要找我的話
Well, you know what? If you need me,
我會在賓克家的暖身派對 就在...
I'm gonna be pre-gaming in Binker's loft in...
一個廢棄的罐頭廠
an abandoned cannery
老泡菜街區那里
in the old pickle district.
感覺他家通風就很棒
Sounds drafty.
好球
Nice roll.
地滾球的戰局比我害怕的還要糟糕
The bocce situation was worse than I feared.
我得把場地奪回到
I had to get the range back
日出揮桿手的手中
in the hands of the Sunrise Swingers.
聽我說 這事別張揚
Listen, I, uh, got to be discreet.
我似乎深入敵后了
Uh, I'm sort of behind enemy lines here.
但是如果我沒搞錯的話
But, uh, if I'm not mistaken,
你也是我們的一員
you're a fellow, uh,
-揮桿手[換妻俱樂部] -你說什么
- "Swinger." - Excuse me?
沒事沒事 我理解 只是...
No, no, it's okay. I'm cool. It's just that I, uh...
我在試著搞點事情
I'm trying to get something started here.
我是說 毫無疑問我們得秘密見面
I mean, uh, of course we have to meet in secrecy,
但我也不介意在我家舉辦
but I don't mind hosting at my house.
-你不會真的在... -夫人 醒醒吧
- Are you actually suggesting... - Lady, wake up.
我們的生活方式正在遭襲
Our way of life is under attack.
很快 我們人都湊不夠一場
Pretty soon, there won't be enough of us
完整的四人對抗賽[性愛]了
for a decent foursome.
我得走了
I have to go.
好吧 考慮一下我說的話
Okay. Well, just think about it.
-就這樣 你考慮考慮吧 -好
- That's all. Just think about it. - Okay.
-值得一試 是吧 -什么
- Worth a shot, huh? - What?
我才不是這個意思
No, that's not what I meant.
這就是你們地滾球玩家所關心的嗎
Oh, that's what you bocce players are about, huh?
發現什么好的 就要毀掉它
You find something nice, and you ruin it.
那是施蒂格利茨博士
That's Dr. Stieglitz.
他有這個獎項贏家的最后決定權
He makes the final decision on the award.
他聰明又嚇人 令人過目難忘
He's brilliant and scary and impossible to impress.
我知道這話聽起來像老爸賣瓜
Hey, I know this is your dad talking,
但你自己也很聰明又嚇人
but you're pretty brilliant and scary
令人過目難忘啊
and impossible yourself.
好吧 我已經露過面了
Okay. I've made an appearance.
-我們應該可以走了 -別這樣 艾麗克斯
- I think we can go. - Come on, now, Alex.
這是為你舉辦的派對
This is a party in your honor,
況且你還帶著你私人的啦啦隊長
and you're here with your own personal cheerleader.
-爸爸 我只是... -我知道怎么激勵一群學者
- Dad, I just... - I know how to pump up an academic crowd.
我還激勵過一個辯論隊呢
I had to cheer for the debate team once.
"要有說服力 要啊要有說服力"
"Be persuasive, B-E persuasive."
-"要啊要啊..." -夠了
- "B-E P-E-R-S... " - That's enough.
"媽的 干脆去問薛定諤的貓得了"
"Damn. Might as well ask Schrodinger's cat."
寵物啊
Pets.
我曾經養過一只能用遙控器的金剛鸚鵡
I once had a macaw that could use a remote control.
成天看有線電視 你也許會想...
Watched a lot of cable. You'd think, uh...
它會看動物星球 但它主要看的是電影頻道
You'd think Animal Planet, but it was mostly Cinemax.
我是艾麗克斯的爸爸
I'm Alex's dad.
艾麗克斯 過來這里
Alex, get in here.
實際上 我剛才指的是一個思維實驗
Actually, I was referring to a thought experiment
關于量子力學中的一個悖論
concerning a paradox in quantum mechanics.
是啊 妙哉妙哉
Yes, quite, quite.
你們都是哪里人啊
Where are you all from originally?
太讓人尷尬了
It was so embarrassing.
施蒂格利茨教授是個天才
Professor Stieglitz is a genius.
他才不會喜歡說著"妙哉妙哉"
He doesn't fall for people who pretend to understand him
來假裝聽得懂他的話的人
by saying things like "Quite, quite,"
或者"確實如此" 或者...
or, "Indeed," or...
有道理啊 兄弟
Touche, my good man!
不過說真的 我有個科學問題
But seriously, I-I have a science question
-我總是想不清楚 -要不就再想想
- I've always wondered about. - Uh, maybe keep wondering.
多少量的氦氣能安全地讓嬰兒
Would there be a safe amount of helium you could give a baby
從地面微微飄起呢
that would lift it off the ground?
什么
What?
我不想讓他飄走
Oh. I don't want it to float away.
我只想讓他玩得開心
I-I just want it to have fun.
我們能...
Can we...
你能幫我個忙嗎
Could you do me a favor?
我今天有包裹要送到我宿舍
I'm having a package delivered to my dorm room,
需要有人留在那里簽收
and someone needs to be there to sign for it.
你室友做不了嗎
Can't your roommate do it?
不行 她被驅逐出境了
No. She got deported.
她不是從阿肯色州來的嗎
I thought she was from Arkansas.
是啊 但是她的父母是...賣國賊
Yeah, but her parents were... traitors.
-貝絲和艾倫 -別難過
- Beth and Allen? - Don't feel bad.
我們都被騙了
We all fell for it.
所以你想讓我回你的宿舍
So you want me to go back to your dorm room
坐著等一個包裹嗎
and sit and wait for a package?
沒錯
Yes.
糟糕 寶貝 我...
Oh, sh-shoot, honey. I...
家里也有一個包裹要等我去收 所以...
I have a delivery coming back to the house, too, so...
我得趕緊去了
I should run.
-如果你必需得回去的話 行 -是的 我很抱歉
- Well, if you have to. - Yeah. I'm so sorry.
不過祝你好運 好嗎
But, hey, good luck, okay?
再見 爸爸
Bye, Dad.
我看起來是不是有點...
Uh, did I seem a little...
過于無情 冷漠 沒錯
Zero Kelvin? Cold. Yeah.
所以你覺得我
So you think I was...
就像一組數的總和除以
Like the sum of a group of numbers divided by
這組數的數量 平均數[刻薄]
the number of those numbers? Mean.
怪不得沒人愿意跟你一起編碼 蒂娜
This is why no one wants to code with you, Tina.
你是怎么找到我的
Hey. How in the world did you find me?
你知道那個可以安在孩子手機上的定位軟件吧
You know that app you can put on kids' phones to track them?
我給了你個驚喜 你就在我手機上安這個
You put one on my phone after I surprised you today?
別說了 我已經很內疚了
Don't make me feel worse than I already do.
等等 你贏了
Wait a minute. You won?!
恭喜你
Congratulations!
不用這樣為我高興 我受之有愧
Please don't be happy for me. I can't take it.
我對你太過分了
I was such a jerk to you.
沒有 寶貝 我理解
No, honey, I get it. I, uh...
我知道我讓你尷尬了
I know I can be embarrassing. I...
在聰明人身邊我就是會緊張
I just get nervous around smart people.
有的時候對你也是
Sometimes even you.
我第一次說"妙哉妙哉"的時候
The first time I ever said "Quite, quite"
是你六歲那年 就在你跟我解釋了
was when you were 6 years old and you just told me
植物是怎么產生二氧化碳之后
about how plants make carbon dioxide.
你可能不相信 但是
This may surprise you, but...
有的時候我希望我能更像你
sometimes I wish I was more like you,
你總是能享受生活
the way you're always able to enjoy life.
不管你信不信 我對我爸爸也是這種感覺
Believe it or not, I felt the same way about my dad.
我其實 跟他比是個悲觀主義者
I'm a... I'm a pessimist compared to him.
而他的父親因為笑太多
And his dad actually suffered
得了疝氣
from a smile-induced hernia.
這是惡作劇周
It's prank week,
我卻全程待在圖書館
and I spent the whole time in the library.
有的時候我感覺自己只是經歷了
Sometimes I feel like I just went through
本應該是生命中最美好的四年
the four best years of my life,
而沒有讓這四年
only I forgot to make them
成為我生命中最美好的回憶
the four best years of my life.
大學還沒結束呢
Well, college isn't over.
我可能能幫你彌補一下
And I just may be able to help you
逝去的一些時光
make up for a little lost time.
辣翅智力賽要開始了
Hot Wing Trivia's about to start.
我給你們登記的隊名叫"鄧菲隊"
I have you guys registered as "The Dunphys"?
你怎么
How did you...?
你知道我要來
You knew I was coming?
別忘了你是從哪知道的那個定位軟件
Let's not forget where you learned about that tracking app.
還有一點小變動
And there's one tiny change.
我們的隊名叫無敵鄧菲
We're actually the MacDunphys.
只有我爸爸會認為這種冷知識競賽
Only my dad would think that a trivia game...
紐約三角內衣工廠火災
The Triangle Shirtwaist Fire.
比賽的時候在頭上頂帽子
...where you balance hats on your head,
贏了要喝啤酒
drink beer as a reward...
卡里姆·阿卜杜·賈巴爾[著名籃球明星]
Kareem Abdul-Jabbar.
輸了要吃辣翅
- - ...and eat hot wings as a punishment...
米勒德·菲爾莫爾[總統]
Millard Fillmore!
...最后還要來點蘇格蘭口音
...needed that one last twist of a Scottish accent.
糊涂蛋 噴嚏精
Dopey, Sneezy...
生氣鬼[白雪公主小矮人]
and Grumpy?
有人說生活中最重要的事
Whoever said the most important thing in life
就是拿獎
is winning awards...
他說的也不無道理
...wasn't all wrong.
我還記得格林斯潘先生
I still remember the day Mr. Greenspan
提出"非理性繁榮"這個詞的那天
coined the term "Irrational exuberance."
他洗了個比平常的都久的澡
He had taken a longer than usual tub
當他坐在泡泡浴中的時候
and, as he sat in the soapy water...
我犯了個錯
I had made a mistake.
小卡踏上了一段冒險
Cam was off on an adventure
而我坐在那兒無聊得要死
while I sat there dying of boredom,
周圍全是快要老死的人
surrounded by people dying of natural causes.
我要繼續跳 好嗎
I'm gonna keep the bounce going, okay?
繼續跳
Keep the bounce going.
你知道嗎 動起脖子來
Yeah, you know, it's a little more
-更有感覺 -我的天
- sass in the neck, because... - Oh, my gosh!
米奇爾 你來這里干什么
Mitchell, what are you doing here?
-講座怎么辦 -講座真是要命了
- What about the lecture? - Well, uh, it was deadly.
我還沒到該老的時候心就老了
Yeah, I'm getting old before my time.
帶我一起玩吧 讓我重拾年輕活力吧
Please take me with you! Make me young again!
我的天 我們真高興你來了
Oh, my gosh, we're so happy you're here.
-真的嗎 -當然
- Really? - Yeah, of course.
不說"早跟你說了吧"
No "I told you so"?
不說了 我們年輕人不這樣
No. That's not how my generation does it.
看看你 還這么有勁頭
Well, check you out, still going strong.
你知道嗎 我覺得我吸收年輕勁兒更精神了
Yeah, you know what? I think I'm just feeding off the energy,
我很久沒有感覺這么清醒了呢
because I haven't felt this awake in...
等一下
Hold on just a second.
藍衣服的 說你呢 藍衣服的
Yo, blue guy! Hey, blue shirt!
怎么樣 兄弟
What's up, bro? Hey!
你看我干嘛 你想干嘛
You looking at me? What do you want to do?
你想跳舞嗎 為什么他一直盯著我
You want to dance? Why is he staring at me?
其實 其實我沒覺得他在看你
You know, you know, I don't think he was looking at you.
感覺他是在看我 什么
It seems like he's looking at me. What's...
你是不是有點累了
Are you getting a little tired?
得了吧 我要累了還能這樣
Oh, please. Can a tired guy do this?
我愛這些人
Da! Hey, I love these guys! Whoa.
你認識達里爾嗎 他媽媽是1990年
Oh, did you know Daryl... Daryl's mom was the runner-up
伊利諾伊小姐選美賽的亞軍
in the Miss Illinois pageant in 1990?!
? 那一年我畢業 ?
♪ The year I graduated ♪
? 達里爾的媽媽很美艷 ?
♪ Daryl's mom was hot ♪
你真棒
Fantastic.
小卡 我覺得你要撞墻上了
Cam, I think you might be hitting that wall.
沒有沒有 我沒事 我要
No, no, no, I'm fine. I would...
這個小丑盯著我干什么
What's this clown staring at? Hey!
不不不 不要拿手指我
No, no, no, no, no, don't point at me.
不然我把你的手指
I'll rip your finger off
扯下來喂給你的紅發女友
and feed it to your red-headed girlfriend!
好了 那是個鏡子
Okay, that is a mirror.
而且我知道這件毛衣顯得我胸很大了
And I knew this sweater made me look busty.
為什么我的手在抖
Okay, w-w-why is my hand shaking?
有人往我飲料里下藥了嗎
Did somebody put something in my drink?
你們這堆興奮劑上癮 愛騎小摩托的
Hey! Did one of you Ritalin-addicted millennial
千禧一代是不是有人給我下藥了
scooter jockeys dose me? Huh?
怎么 你們以為能把我這棵大樹放倒嗎
What, you think you can take this tree down, do you?
怎么著 我可是棵參天紅木
Well, guess what! I'm a redwood!
沒錯 你們還沒生出來我就在這了
That's right, I was here before you were born,
你們沒了我也還在這
and I'll be here after you're gone!
他有時候就這樣 他只是需要睡一下
He gets like this. He just needs a nap.
-該睡覺了 -好的
- Nap time. - Okay.
-睡覺 走吧 -不 可是我還不想走
- Nap. Let's go. - No, I don't want to go, though!
-我喜歡我的新朋友 -我知道
- I like my new friends! - Yeah, I know.
你們喜歡我嗎 我可喜歡你們了
Do you guys like me? 'Cause I like you!
我想留下
Yeah. I want to stay!
我對一切都好抱歉
And I'm really sorry about everything.
-你得放開他 -我好抱歉
- You got to let him go. - No, I'm sorry.
你得放開他 沒事的
You got to let him go. It's okay.
-謝謝你 -我好抱歉
- Thank you. - I'm so sorry.
-再見 -我不知道你沒盯著我看
- Bye-bye. - I didn't know you weren't staring at me.
-沒事的 -不 我不想走
- Shh. It's okay. - No, I don't want to go.
伊麗莎白時代社團的獨白非常成功
I nailed my monologues for the Elizabethan Society.
吾認為我能成為新一任莉齊
Methinks you're looking at a brand-new Lizzie.
這么說"窩認為"沒錯
So it is "Methinks."
那我說的時候杰怎么總糾正我
So, why does Jay correct me every time I say that?
杰 來客人了 別躲在臥室里
Jay, we have company! Do not hide in the bedroom.
你好
Hello.
多謝你特意過來
Thank you for coming.
-你男朋友在哪 -他在停車
- Where's the boyfriend? - He's just parking.
跟你說 我們在來的路上發現一件事
And, you know, we realized something on the way over,
有點尷尬
and it's a little awkward.
是開胃菜 我馬上回來
Those are my hors d'oeuvres. I'll be back.
-給自己弄杯喝的 -好
- Make yourself a drink. - Okay.
性感辣妹
Hey, hot stuff.
你確定這一點也不詭異嗎
Are you sure this isn't a little weird?
我沒想到我們要幫助的情侶
Well, I wasn't expecting the couple we'd be helping out
會是我外公和他妻子 但是
to be my grandpa and his wife, but...
我們的戀情
our relationship was gonna be
-遲早要公開的 -是啊
- out in the open eventually. - Yeah.
我基本已經和所有認識的人炫耀過了
I kind of bragged about it to everyone I know.
你可真甜
Oh, you're so sweet.
是我女兒
My daughter.
她想叫朋友來玩 我說過不準辦派對
She wants to have friends over. I said no parties.
你放松
Hey, you relax.
丹尼絲 是時候輪到你媽媽與我出來放松一晚了
Denise, your mother and I deserve one night off.
俱樂部的女士
The lady from the club!
要么她不知道我是歌洛莉亞的丈夫
Either she didn't know I was Gloria's husband
事態馬上會變得非常尷尬
and things were about to get very awkward,
要么她知道 她是因為我無意的提議
or she did know and she was here to follow up
來玩"四人行"了
on my accidental proposition.
老天 我真討厭家里來人
God, I hate company!
性感辣妹
Hey, hot stuff.
你的小狼狗呢
Where's your boy toy?
他在打電話 不過我得說一聲
Oh, he's making a phone call. Got to say, though,
我覺得有點尷尬 因為原來
I feel kind of awkward because, turns out,
-他跟歌洛莉亞有親戚關系 -什么
- he's related to Gloria. - What?
是我女兒 我得處理一下 抱歉
My daughter. I have to handle this. Sorry.
克萊爾 我有個大消息
Claire, I have big news.
老天 假如是我想的那個
Oh, God. If it's what I think it is,
我不知道你該不該這樣做
I don't know if that's a good idea.
我知道 人們會說
I know. People will say
我過于迷戀老舊的人和事了
I've taken my love of old things too far.
但我很開心
But I'm happy.
不是我炫耀 但我是第一個進去的拉丁裔
And not to brag, but I'm the first Latino to get in there.
老天 我覺得我有點責任
Oh, boy. I feel sort of responsible for this.
我認為這更歸功于我的表現
Um, I think it has a little more to do with my performance.
我表現十分杰出
I distinguished myself
所有的女性重點部分都被我征服了
when I did literally all the girl parts.
我得去往臉上潑點水
I need to go splash some water on my face.
等一下 你最近有在做仰臥起坐嗎
Wait a minute. Have you been doing sit-ups?
每晚都做 為了持久力
Oh, every night for stamina.
不然我不會表現得那么好
I would not have been able to perform without it.
我甚至還加入了一些舌頭練習
I even threw in some tongue exercises
因為我的悍婦[《馴悍記》]要好久才到高潮
because my "Shrew" was taking forever.
老天
Oh, God.
爸 你又在躲什么
Dad, what are you hiding from?
等我告訴你我在俱樂部
You'll know after I tell you
和那女人說了什么 你就知道了
what I said to that woman from the club.
她怎么來了
What is she doing here?
-她是來讓你脫下這身衣服的 -你知道了啊
- She's trying to get you out of those clothes. - You know?
是的 我們在瑜伽課上談過了
Yes! We talked about it at yoga.
那是歌洛莉亞的主意
It was Gloria's idea.
我只是來當潤滑油作用的
I just came along to grease the wheels.
什么 你說這句前我本來差點要同意了
What?! I was almost considering it until you added that part.
我得去往臉上潑點水
I gotta splash water on my face.
這地方真冷清 想走嗎
This place is dead. Want to bounce?
不 我們不必和一大群人一起
No, we don't have to be around
才能玩得盡興啊
a big group of people to have fun.
盧克 不
Luke, no!
她有男朋友了
She has a boyfriend.
是啊 就是我
Yeah, me.
不 是俱樂部的某個小伙子
No, it's some young guy from the club...
老天
Oh, boy.
歌洛莉亞 你知道曼尼的事嗎
Gloria, do you know what's going on with Manny?
你認為他能藏住那個秘密嗎
Uh, do you think that he can keep that a secret?
他們不得不穿各種奇怪的衣服
They have to wear all kind of weird outfits
每次做起來都得穿
every time they do it.
媽
Hey, Ma.
盧克 盧克 別碰曼尼的女朋友
Luke... Luke, get your hands off Manny's girlfriend.
-那不是我女朋友 -什么
- That's not my girlfriend. - What?
那我們剛才討論的是什么
Then what were we just talking about?
伊麗莎白時代社團 今晚第一次聚會
The Elizabethan Society. M-My first meeting's tonight.
-我好糊涂 -再明白不過了
- I'm so confused. - It's plain as day.
這女人是過來和我玩換妻的
This woman is here to swing with me.
到此為止 這是我的底線
That's it. That's where I draw the line.
怎么會發生這種事
How did this happen?
我告訴你怎么會發生這種事
I'll tell you how this happened.
因為沒有人愿意當壞人
Because nobody was willing to say
說出逆耳的忠言
what needs to be said.
不行 不行 不行
No. No. No.
絕對不行
And hell no.
那是你對得了B-的感覺 丹尼絲
It's how you feel about the B-minus, Denise,
而不是你媽和我的感覺
not how your mother and I feel about it.
不 我沒不同意你去阿姆斯特丹
No, I'm not saying no to the Amsterdam trip.
是的 聽起來會是很好玩的暑假
Yeah, it sounds like a fun summer,
但這寫在大學申請上好看嗎
but how is that gonna look on a college application?
我們稍后再談
We'll talk about it later.
我當然為你驕傲了
Of course I'm proud of you.
媽
Hey, Mom.
盧克 寶貝 你介意幫我拿一下
Hey, Luke. Honey, would you mind getting me
架子頂層的沙拉碗嗎
that salad bowl off the top shelf?
好的
Yep.
我知道只有我喜歡
I know I'm the only one,
但這是我的最愛
but it is my favorite.
不必道歉 老媽 你知道自己喜歡什么
Don't apologize, Mom. You know what you like.
算了 我不吃了
Never mind. I'm good.